let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The ratio of contributions made by the electric field and magnetic field components, to the intensity of an electromagnetic wave is (where, c = speed of electromagnetic waves)",
    answer: "c:1",
    options: [
      "1:2",
      "1:1",
      "1:c",
      "c:1"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "In a certain region of space with volume 0.2 cubic meter, the electric potential is found to be 5 V throughout. The magnitude of electric field in this region is",
    answer: "Zero",
    options: [
      "0.5 N/C",
      "5 N/C",
      "1 N/C",
      "Zero"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "A screw gauge has least count of 0.01 mm and there are 50 divisions in its circular scale. The pitch of the screw gauge is",
    answer: "0.5 mm",
    options: [
      "0.25 mm",
      "1.0 mm",
      "0.5 mm",
      "0.01 mm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In Young’s double slit experiment, if the separation between coherent sources is halved and the distance of the screen from the coherent sources is doubled, then the fringe width becomes",
    answer: "Four times",
    options: [
      "Half",
      "Four times",
      "One-fourth",
      "Double"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Taking into account of the significant figures, what is the value of 9.99 m − 0.0099 m?",
    answer: "9.980 m",
    options: [
      "9.98 m",
      "9.980 m",
      "9.9 m",
      "9.9801 m"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A capillary tube of radius r is immersed in water a water rises in it to a height h. The mass of the water in the capillary tube is 5 g. Another capillary tube of radius 2r is immersed in water. The mass of water that will rise in this tube is",
    answer: "2.5 g",
    options: [
      "5.0 g",
      "10.0 g",
      "2.5 g",
      "20.0 g"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "A body weighs 72 N on the surface of the earth. What is the gravitational force on it, at a height equal to half of radius of the earth?",
    answer: "32 N",
    options: [
      "32 N",
      "30 N",
      "25 N",
      "48 N"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Two particles of mass 5 kg and 10 kg respectively are attached to the two ends of a rigid rod of length 1 m with negligible mass. The centre of mass of the system from the 5 kg particle is nearly at a distance of",
    answer: "67 cm",
    options: [
      "60 cm",
      "67 cm",
      "57 cm",
      "33 cm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The increase in the width of the depletion region in a p-n junction diode is due to",
    answer: "Reverse bias only",
    options: [
      "Reverse bias only",
      "Both forward bias and reverse bias",
      "Increase in forward current",
      "Forward bias only"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Light of frequency 1.5 times the threshold frequency is incident on a photosensitive material. What will be the photoelectric current if the frequency is halved and intensity is doubled?",
    answer: "Zero",
    options: [
      "Four Times",
      "One Fourth",
      "Zero",
      "Doubled"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "In a guitar, two strings A and B made of same material are slightly out of tune and produce beats of frequency 6 Hz. When tension in B is slightly decreased, the beat frequency increases to 7 Hz. If the frequency of A is 530 Hz, the original frequency of B will be",
    answer: "524 Hz",
    options: [
      "524 Hz",
      "536 Hz",
      "537 Hz",
      "523 Hz"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The solids which have the negative temperature coefficient of resistance are",
    answer: "Insulators and Semiconductors",
    options: [
      "Insulators Only",
      "Semiconductors Only",
      "Insulators and Semiconductors",
      "Metals"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "For transistor action, which of the following statements is correct?",
    answer: "The base region must be very thin and lightly doped",
    options: [
      "Base, emitter and collector regions should have same size.",
      "Both emitter junction as well as the collector junction are forward biased",
      "The base region must be very thin and lightly doped",
      "Base, emitter and collector regions should have same dopping concentrations"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "A body is executing simple harmonic motion with frequency n, the frequency of its potential energy is",
    answer: "2n",
    options: [
      "n",
      "2n",
      "3n",
      "4n"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "A spring is stretched by 5 cm by a force 10 N. The time period of the oscillations when a mass of 2 kg is suspended by it is",
    answer: "0.628 s",
    options: [
      "0.0628 s",
      "6.28 s",
      "3.14 s",
      "0.628 s"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "A nucleus with mass number 240 breaks into two fragments each of mass number 120, the binding energy per nucleon of unfragmented nuclei is 7.6 MeV while that of fragments is 8.5 MeV. The",
    answer: "216 MeV",
    options: [
      "0.9 MeV",
      "9.4 MeV",
      "804 MeV",
      "216 MeV"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "A screw gauge gives the following readings when used to measure the diameter of a wire Main scale reading : 0 mm Circular scale reading : 52 divisions Given that, 1 mm on main scale corresponds to 100 divisions on the circular scale. The diameter of the wire from the above data is",
    answer: "0.052 cm",
    options: [
      "0.52 cm",
      "0.026 cm",
      "0.26 cm",
      "0.052 cm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "The escape velocity from the Earth’s surface is v. The escape velocity from the surface of another planet having a radius, four times that of Earth and same mass density is",
    answer: "4 v",
    options: [
      "v",
      "3 v",
      "2 v",
      "4 v"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "In a potentiometer circuit, a cell of emf 1.5 V gives balance point at 36 cm length of wire. If another cell of emf 2.5 V replaces the first cell, then at what length of the wire, the balance point occurs?",
    answer: "60 cm",
    options: [
      "60 cm",
      "21.6 cm",
      "64 cm",
      "62 cm"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "The velocity of a small ball of mass M and density d when dropped in a container filled with glycerine becomes constant after some time. If the density of glycerine is d/2, then the viscous force acting on the ball will be",
    answer: "Mg/2",
    options: [
      "Mg",
      "Mg/2",
      "3/2*Mg",
      "2 Mg"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "A lens of large focal length and large aperture is best suited as an objective of an astronomical telescope, since",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "a large aperture contributes to the quality and visibility of the images",
      "a large area of the objective ensures better light gathering power",
      "a large aperture provides a better resolution",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "The electron concentration in an n-type semiconductor is the same as hole concentration in a p-type semiconductor. An external field (electric) is applied across each of them. Compare the currents in them.",
    answer: "Current in n-type> Current in p-type",
    options: [
      "Current in n-type = Current in p-type",
      "Current in p-type > Current in n-type",
      "Current in n-type> Current in p-type",
      "No current will flow in p-type. current will only flow in n-type"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "Polar molecules are the molecules",
    answer: "having a permanent electric dipole moment",
    options: [
      "having zero dipole moment",
      "acquire a dipole moment only in the presence of electric field due to displacement of charges.",
      "acquire a dipole moment only when magnetic field is absent",
      "having a permanent electric dipole moment"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Water falls from a height of 60 m at the rate of 15 kg/s to operate a turbine. The losses due to frictional force are 10% of the input energy. How much power is generated by the turbine?",
    answer: "8.1 Kw",
    options: [
      "10.2 Kw",
      "8.1 Kw",
      "7.0 Kw",
      "12.3 Kw"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "A ball of mass 0.15 kg is dropped from a height 10 m, strikes the ground and rebounds to the same height. The magnitude of impulse imparted to the ball is nearly",
    answer: "4.2 kg-m/s",
    options: [
      "0",
      "4.2 kg-m/s",
      "2.1 kg-m/s",
      "1.4 kg-m/s"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "Twenty seven drops of same size are charged at 220 V each. They combine to form a bigger drop. Calculate the potential of the bigger drop",
    answer: "1980 V",
    options: [
      "1320 V",
      "1980 V",
      "660 V",
      "440 V"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "A series L-C-R circuit containing 5.0 H inductor, 80 μF capacitor and 40 W resistor is connected to 230 V variable frequency AC source. The angular frequencies of the source at which power transferred to the circuit is half the power at the resonant angular frequency are likely to be",
    answer: "46 rad/s and 54 rad/s",
    options: [
      "25 rad/s and 75 rad/s",
      "50 rad/s and 25 rad/s",
      "46 rad/s and 54 rad/s",
      "42 rad/s and 58 rad/s"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "A step down transformer connected to an AC mains supply of 220 V is made to operate at 11 V, 44 W lamp. Ignoring power losses in the transformer, what is the current in the primary circuit ?",
    answer: "0.2 A",
    options: [
      "2 A",
      "0.2 A",
      "4 A",
      "0.4 A"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "The effective resistance of a parallel connection that consists of four wires of equal length, equal area of cross-section and same material is 0.25 W. What will be the effective resistance if they are connected in series?",
    answer: "4 W",
    options: [
      "4 W",
      "2 W",
      "0.25 W",
      "1 W"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "A convex lens A of focal length 20 cm and a concave lens B of focal length 5 cm are kept along the same axis with a distance d between them. If a parallel beam of light falling on A leaves B as a parallel beam, then the distance d (in cm) will be",
    answer: "15",
    options: [
      "30",
      "15",
      "20",
      "25"
    ]
  },
];